<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intricate Mechanisms</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Intricate Mechanisms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minding your Ps and Qs</title>
      <link>/2020/05/17/p-vs-q/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/17/p-vs-q/</guid>
      <description>I have a lot of respect for the UK actuarial exams, and in some ways that respect has actually increased since I gave up on them a few years back.
Broadly speaking: the earlier actuarial exams get you up to speed with a bunch of essential technical topics, whilst the later exams teach you how to apply those topics without falling into any of a few hundred known pitfalls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tables in R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2020/05/16/tables-in-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/16/tables-in-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Something that took me a while to grasp when I was younger is that two people can have legitimately different experiences of a person or place. “He’s always positive and smiling,” says the big boss. “He’s really grumpy and tends to lash out,” says the subordinate. “He’s cheerful and a bit flirty,” says the co-worker. The executive assistant agrees but adds that she finds the flirting a bit creepy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Write Stuff</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/i-write-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/i-write-stuff/</guid>
      <description>This post is a log of publicly-available content I&amp;rsquo;ve produced for third parties. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it in future as new stuff lands.
IFoA DS-MIG I&amp;rsquo;ve written on data science for the Institute and Faculty of Actuaries, the UK&amp;rsquo;s actuarial professional body, as part of my involvement in their Data Science Member Interest Group (I&amp;rsquo;m a workstream lead). These are aimed at a professional audience, so if you&amp;rsquo;re used to Medium.com-style articles then you may find them a bit turgid, but they hopefully provide a good overview of a few key topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science is Different</title>
      <link>/2020/05/13/data-science-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/13/data-science-different/</guid>
      <description>Data science is fast emerging as one of the core concepts with which companies and professionals must grapple. However, as with most such concepts, it lives a double life: half useful technical term, half content-free buzzword.
In its incarnation as a technical term, what it really represents is:
 The convergence of data analysis techniques from a wide range of scientific fields. Until recently, every scientific field had its own techniques and terminology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R Blogdown on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>/2020/05/11/getting-started-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/11/getting-started-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Your mission, should you choose to accept it&amp;hellip; I recently stumbled back across an essay that I remember caught my attention a couple years back. Its premise: if you want to be a data scientist, start a blog. It&amp;rsquo;ll give you practice, help you build a portfolio, and attract constructive critical feedback.
As an aspiring data scientist, what else could I do but take this excellent advice? Although I think I may be on the wrong Internet for that last point :-/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
